Guide to the Herman R. Brown Papers 1946-1985 (Bulk 1946-1951) MS 80
@ 2011 New-York Historical Society
Herman R. Brown Papers
1946-1985 (bulk 1946-1951)
MS 80
@ 2011 New-York Historical Society
0.43 Linear feet (1 box)
Correspondence involving Herman R. Brown, an African- American solider and Mary K. Groom, married name Cox. Brown and Groom sent love letters to each other, which continued even after each was married to other people. The majority of the letters are from Brown to Groom from 1946-1951. Included are some letters from friends and others.
[material specific details such as mathematical data, scale for maps, physical presentation data for music records]
Custodial History note
Access Restrictions
Open to qualified researchers.
Photocopying undertaken by staff only. Limited to twenty exposures of stable, unbound material per day. (Researchers may not accrue unused copy amounts from previous days.) See guidelines in Reading room for details.
Biographical Note
1946 Apr. Herman Richard Brown in army stationed in New Rochelle, New York
1946 June Brown stationed at Fort McClellan, Alabama
1946 July Brown asks Mary Groom to marry him; she never answers him
1946 Sept. Brown stationed at Camp Stoneman, California
1946 Oct. Brown stationed in Japan
Late 1946 Brown returns from Japan to California
1948 Brown stationed at Fort Lawton, Washington
Early 1949 Mary Groom marries Walter E. Cox, Jr.
1956 July Brown stationed in Germany/Cox working for army
1958 Apr. Brown stationed at Fort Hood, Texas
1961 Oct. Brown living in Anchorage, Alaska
Scope and Content Note
The Herman R. Brown Papers mainly consist of correspondence between Herman R. Brown, an African-American solider and Mary Groom Cox. Brown is from New Rochelle and Groom is from the Bronx. There are approximately 145 letters (Folders 1-13). The letters are primarily of a personal nature between Herman Brown and Mary Groom. The collection consists of love letters Brown and Cox wrote to each other before and after they were married to others. It is unclear in the letters why the two never married each other. The other letters consist of correspondence from friends and businesses. The letters from their friends mostly focus on Brown and Cox's relationship. Brown never discusses life in the army or the places he is stationed.
Arrangement
The letters are arranged chronologically.
Brown, Herman Richard; Cox, Mary Kathryn Groom;; African American soldiers; African American women; Marriage
  - Correspondence between Brown and Cox, Undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence between Brown and Cox, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence between Brown and Cox, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence between Brown and Cox, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence between Brown and Cox, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence between Brown and Cox, 1950 Jan.- 1950 Apr. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence between Brown and Cox, 1950 May - 1950 Oct. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence between Brown and Cox, 1951-1952 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence between Brown and Cox, 1955-1956 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence between Brown and Cox, 1958-1959 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence between Brown and Cox, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence between Brown and Cox, 1962-1963 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, others, 1946-1985 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Miscellaneous-picture of two African-American males, hotel receipt, notes, annulment agreement of Mary Cox and Walter E. Cox, Jr., 1958, Undated (Box 1, Folder 14)